Rob Hunter :: Software Engineering Professional

Waterloo, Ontario, Canada • rphunter@gmail.com

PERFORMANCE PROFILE

Self-motivated, highly adaptable, and organized software engineering professional with eight years of experience specializing in automated build and test systems. Outstanding troubleshooting and problem solving skills, with a proven ability to identify and solve root-cause issues.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Quality assurance and control
- Commercialization engineering
- Software build master
- Software design and development
- Process management
- Team management

TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES

Programming

- C, C++
- C#
- Python
- Pascal
- VB6, VB.NET
- Java
- Batch Scripting
- VBScript

Technologies

- Build/Test Automation
- SCCM
- Continuous Integration
- Windows Installer
- Software License Protection
- SharePoint
- Virtualization
- Wikis

Processes

- Scrum
- Lean
- TDD
- Agile Testing
- Usability Testing
- Software Compliance
- Commercial Deployment
- Trade Compliance

Rob Hunter

TOOLS EXPERIENCE

Quality Assurance Tools

- TestComplete
- QTP/WinRunner
- MSTest with dotCover
- NUnit with NCover
- SandCastle
- FxCop

Build Tools

- TeamCity
- TFS TeamBuild
- CruiseControl.NET
- MSBuild
- NAnt
- FinalBuilder

SCCM/ALM

- TFS
- StarTeam
- Git

Development Environments

- Visual Studio
- C++ Builder
- Delphi
- Eclipse

Installation Authoring

- WIX
- Wise Installation Studio
- Inno Setup
- InstallShield
- NSIS

Other

- Morae
- Reprise License Manager
- Aladdin HASP
- VMWare Workstation
- DemoShield

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Commercialization Engineering Process Lead

Schlumberger Canada Limited (Schlumberger Water Services)

* Currently employed in this position

Nov 2010-Present Waterloo, ON

Responsible for coordinating all commercial deployment activities for all software products developed in Waterloo office, in this role I am also working to improve software quality in all aspects of the Agile quadrants, while enforcing stricter commercialization deadlines. Emphasis has been on introducing Agile processes and tools, empowering co-workers, strengthening our internship program, and shipping software to schedule. This role includes managing the test team, maintaining the build and testing infrastructure, and overseeing the SDLC.

- Incorporated agile development and testing practices into new development projects; piloting Scrum, TDD, usability testing, and UI test automation
- Refactored installers and tests to be automatable achieving 100% build automation and 70% UI test automation to reduce release testing cycles to under a week
- Product owner for "shared components" including license protection controls, automatic update notification, application analytics used across software portfolio

Rob Hunter

QA/QC Coordinator for Water Services Software

Schlumberger Canada Limited (Schlumberger Water Services)

Apr 2008-Nov 2010 Waterloo, ON

In this role, in addition to my previous responsibilities of Build and Deployment Specialist, I was given the additional responsibility of managing the QA/QC team, which included a tester, a technical writer, and a co-op student. Through 2009 and 2010, I also co-managed the technical support team of three with the sales manager. I additionally took on the management of two software development projects.

- Managed QA/QC team, and initiated co-op student recruitment
- Managed technical support team and handled escalated client installation, deployment, and licensing issues
- Introduced continuous integration systems and improved build performance
- Refactored installation packages to improve installation user experience
- Led a project to replace the licensing protection across all software products developed in Waterloo, developed the original design and prototypes, and managed the development and integration
- Managed an out-sourced project to deploy multiple software applications in a streamlined manner through a chained installation

Software Build and Deployment Specialist

Schlumberger Canada Limited (Schlumberger Water Services)

May 2006-Apr 2008 Waterloo, ON

I was hired out of university by Schlumberger for the new build and deployment specialist role. This role was originally to manually integrate software build components into installation packages, and act as a collaboration point of contact between the software development, marketing, and sales departments for all commercialization activities. I broadened the role to include source control management, automation of component integration, automated build scheduling, and contributing to the in-house SDLC processes.

- Restructured the source control configuration to improve branching scenarios
- Performed all independent builds of water services software products
- Automated the build process of software products and automate API documentation generation, unit test running and coverage, and static code analysis
- Improved build times and increase frequency of integration builds
- Authored installation packages
- Responsible for the release of software, including the update of release process to include trade compliance procedures, license auditing, and updated EULA

Rob Hunter

EDUCATION

University of Waterloo, Waterloo, ON

Bachelor of Applied Science in Computer Engineering (Co-op), 2006

COOPERATIVE EDUCATION EXPERIENCE

Control Systems Software Developer

Jan 2005-Apr 2005 & Sept 2005-Dec 2005

ATS Automation Tooling Systems Inc.

Cambridge, ON

- Designed and implemented graphical search and XML logging tools in C++
- Ported a C++ matrix library and implemented a rigid transformations library in ICI

Payload Assistant

May 2004-Aug 2004

Canadian Space Agency

St. Hubert, QC

- Incorporated NASA's Telescience Resource Kit software into operations support center for Canadian payloads on the International Space Station
- Created guidelines for creating user interfaces with C++/Visual Basic .NET

Assistant Building Systems Engineer

Sept 2003-Dec 2003

Dufferin-Peel Catholic District School Board

Mississauga, ON

- Designed, wrote, and integrated security and backup systems in C++ with WIN32
 API for remote building automation systems (HVAC control) computers
- Completed and launched School Board Archiving Program using File Maker Pro

Software Developer

May 2002-Aug 2002 & Jan 2003-Apr 2003

Synexus Global Inc.

Niagara Falls, ON

- Designed and prototyped password encryption system for database access
- Developed methods for proxy classes in CORBA project